

# sebastián\_holgado

# Front End Developer & UI Designer

I am a Web Developer with strong focus on Design and Usability, creating powerful applications that users enjoy using. Reading and improving my skills, as well as obtaining new ones are part of my daily routine. I am also an educator at heart, being an assistant professor in college and providing training at work. I also enjoy taking photographs and travelling!

# **Contact Info**

E-MAIL

holgado.sebastian@gmail.com PHONE

+54 221 153047535

WEBSITE

ohsebastian.com

**SKYPE** holgado.sebastian

## **Work Experience**

Front End Developer Ssr. - Despegar.com

MARCH 2015 - PRESENT

Developer for one of the largest travel agencies in Latin America with more than 700000 hits a month, working on client sided projects and applications.

- ${\color{blue} \bullet}$  Created and mantained responsive single page applications using AngularJS, SASS, Grunt, Java and NodeJS
- O Worked with Product Analysts, UI Designers, UI Developers and Back End Developers
- Mantained and versioned code using GIT
- O Deployed applications to production using the command line, Jenkins and other tools
- Created and mantained Grunt tasks
- O Created responsive e-mail templates
- O Partaken as an educator for in-company UI development courses and a trainee program
- O Read and written documentation

#### UI Designer & Developer - Freelance

2013 - PRESENT

- ${\bf O}$  Designed and developed responsive websites and landing pages
- O Deployed sites to production using Heroku, OpenShift and FTP
- O Re-styled Wordpress themes and mantained Wordpress sites
- O Created logos and digital brand identities

#### Co-Founder / Developer - ISM Custom Design

SEPTEMBER 2013 - MARCH 2015

Co-founder of a small Design Studio located in the city on La Plata, that catered to small and medium sized clients. With focus on Identity Design and Web Development.

- O Designed graphic pieces, such and logos, personal cards and brochures
- O Designed and developed responsive websites
- O Set up client meetings
- O Briefed about progress and delivered finished projects to clients

#### **QA Analyst** - Globant

OCTOBER 2010 - MARCH 2012

Game tester for EA developed games, with a focus on team work.

- O Ad-hoc testing
- O Regression testing

### **Education**

Multimedia Design - Universidad Nacional de La Plata 3 YEARS

With a strong focus on User Interface Design and User Experience, college has given me the tools and the passion to achieve my goals should they be designing complex, yet intuitive interfaces, or developing them.

## Involvement

I was an Assistant Professor in College. I attended several design and usability conferences, including Trimarchi and IXDA La Plata. I was also involved in several audiovisual projects, filming, editing, photographing and creating digital brands for music bands.

## Skills

My main focus is Front End Development, but I'm no stranger to most design tools included in the Adobe Package.

#### Development



## Design



## Languages

Spanish - Native

English - Advanced
FIRST CERTIFICATE (UNIVERSITY OF CAMBRIDGE)

Japanese - Beginner
YONKYU (THE JAPAN FOUNDATION AND
JAPAN EDUCATIONAL EXCHANGES AND
SERVICES)

Swedish - Beginner SELF-TAUGHT